# Columbus, OH 740-525-5327 connie@cskomra.com

# **CONNIE SKOMRA**

cskomra.github.io github.com/cskomra linkedin/in/connieskomra

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and finance industries. Skilled in C#, .NET, and Python Full Stack Development. Strong entrepreneur with Nanodegrees in Front End and Full Stack Web Development from Udacity.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: C#, JAVA, Python, SQL, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3

Frameworks/Libraries: .NET, jQuery, AngularJS, Bootstrap, Flask, Grunt, Knockout IDEs: Visual Studio, SQL Server Management Studio, Android Studio, Eclipse, PyCharm

Other: Git/GitHub, GAE, AWS, OAuth2, Scrum, Lean Startup

## **CERTIFICATES**

- FULL STACK C#/.NET DEVELOPER CERTIFICATTION, Blue Ocean Coding, 2017 (In Progress)
- FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER NANODEGREE, Udacity, 2016

Projects: Movie Trailer Website, Multi-user Blog, Swiss Tournament Pairing System, Item Catalog, Game API, Linux Server Configuration

• FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER NANODEGREE, Udacity, 2015

Projects: Mockup, Portfolio, Web Arcade Game, Neighborhood Map, Website Optimization, Feedreader Testing

## **EXPERIENCE**

## STRATEGIC PERSONAL FINANCE, LLC, Founder, 2015 • Powell, Ohio

- Startup activities including customer and product development
- Completed Rev1 Ventures' Concept Academy

## TEMEDA, LLC, Manager Edge Systems, 07/2013 - 05/2014 • Chicago, IL

- · Captured business requirements from stakeholders
- Generated mockups using IBM Framework Manager, Cognos, and LogiAnalytics
- Created star schema queries to support business intelligence system
- Designed back-end return on investment engine for new product development using time-driven activity-based costing methods

# HOMESCHOOLING my children, 2008 - Present • Powell, Ohio

# PEOPLES BANK, N.A., IT Specialist, 06/2006 - 03/2008 • Marietta, Ohio

- Saved 60% manger/employee time spent on annual performance reviews by integrating MS SQL Server 2008
   Kronos HR system with IBM Domino and Lotus Notes.
- Led corporate-wide technical support for over 600 users, 100 data servers, 50 locations, and 100+ software systems and applications, working with team of 8.
- Directed all Lotus Notes and Domino development in Version 7. Managed Lotus Notes and Domino Domain and Enterprise Server Administration and development.
- Orchestrated collaborative learning program with team members and executive players to present new ideas/technologies for operational improvements.

# B2B DEVELOPMENT SERVICES, Consultant/Founder, 04/2004 - 06/2006 • Whipple, Ohio

- Generated 40% decrease in website management costs, 5% reduction in publication errors, and 80% increase in relevant website content published.
- Spearheaded recovery of \$250K of FEMA reimbursable man-hour and material-usage expenses for City of Marietta, and saved additional \$100K in hard-to-recover expenses by automating river-level data on website and providing critical information to residents in area hit by major flooding.

## APACHETA CORPORATION, IT Director, 07/2003 - 04/2004 • San Diego, California

- Led establishment of technology aspect of start-up company, working with executive management to facilitate
  effective communications and tracking systems
- Saved \$50K in unnecessary travel expenses by planning and completing corporate migration from Exchange Outlook to Domino Lotus Notes ND6.5 and Sametime.
- Distributed Source Code Management, and Bug Tracking systems, email, instant messaging, for operations within 9 states, Canada, and Beijing.

## ECSOFT, INC., Partner/Owner/Consultant, 10/1999 - 04/2001 • Sterling, Virginia

- Negotiated win-win transfer of several client projects from Delfin Systems to ECSoft.
- Generated excellent reputation for quality Domino development services in the NOVA area, achieving high rates of customer satisfaction and delivering results.
- Directed software and application development; and managed administrative aspects of business, from bookkeeping and payroll to sales and marketing.

#### DELFIN SYSTEMS, Senior Software Engineer, 02/1999 - 10/1999 • Fairfax, Virginia

- Designed, developed, and localized interactive content management application for Travel Industry using Domino R5 and Global Workbench
- Saved client \$60K in annual developer-salary expenses by providing relevant, localized travel content without the need for ongoing development staff.
- Revitalized failing project with large corporate client to recover relationship and complete project deliverables, resulting in high level of client satisfaction.

# DELOITTE & TOUCHE LLP, Senior Software Developer, 10/1998 - 02/1999 • Hermitage, TN

- Led technical development of global R5 Notes client/server and web-based Electronic Project Management system.
- Gathered requirements from internal and external clients to architect, design, and develop solutions to complex business problems.
- Researched and proposed application architecture improvements by analyzing and correcting performance issues.
- Mentored developers in scripting and Web programming techniques.

## **EDUCATION**

## Bachelor of Arts in Music, Minor in Business Management

Marietta College, Marietta, Ohio

## Masters level IT/IS degree program courses: GPA 4.0

- Object Oriented Programming with Java
- Software Engineering
- Leader Tech-Based Organizations
- Emerging Technologies
- Strategic Application of Technology
- Foundations of Strategy, Systems, and Technology

# **VOLUNTEERING**

# National Leadership Program Director, Omega Phi Alpha, 2015 - 2016

 Led and managed team of appointees to develop and deliver a comprehensive leadership certification program for all levels of membership.

## Robotics Coach and Mentor, FIRST Lego League, 2012 - 2015

- Started 5 teams / Coached 3 teams
- Influenced 50 kids to get involved in STEM
- Awarded First place: Innovative Solution (Silicon Chips Team 6370, State of WV)